Let's discuss about the system UI architecture.
So in this session, we will have a look at some of the most important system UI classes.
And later, we will have a code walkthrough through this classes.
Well, as we can see, the system UI components share some common characteristics like, for example,
the status bar, navigation bar, Muslim UI, Toast UI, extra, all these components, how these characteristics
in common.
So it has to be initialized.
So the initialization has to be handled for all these components and then it has to change, according
to the state of the system.
So whenever the end of term and always changes, it has to react.
So, for example, the battery charge is lower than it has to show in notifications, right?
That one is that it has to dump blocks.
So this is basically to assist the developers debug these components.
And then when the system started, that should be a corresponding logic, which has to be executed for
all these components.
So for example, when the system is booted, it has to show the status bar.
So and similarly, it has to also show the navigation bar.
So these common logic has to be implemented.
Well, since all the system UI components share these common behavior, so that is an abstract class
on the system UI, which is extended by all these components.
So you'll have a look at all these answers when we do the court walkthrough.
So for now, just understand that there is a system UI abstract class, which is extended by all of
the system UI components.
So there are a few exceptions few system UI components, which doesn't extend system UI, but most of
them do.
So let's switch to intelligence.
It's only how intelligent here with the System UI project open so we can find the System UI class under
the System UI package here.
Yeah.
So as you can see, the System UI is an abstract class.
It has some important methods defined in it.
So the first one is stock method.
As you can see, it's an abstract method.
So this has to be implemented within the subclass.
So, for example, the Ghost UI, which extends the system UI class, should actually implement the
logic for the stop at that.
So we'll see some examples later.
Similarly, we have the own configuration changed.
So this is a callback method.
So this method has to react with some configuration change.
This is basically to handle any system changes.
For example, when the battery charge goes down, it has to show a host so that could be configured
could be defined here.
So you could add some logic here to show an alert or some other mechanism to let the user know that
either has gone down and then we have the dump.
So this is basically for the logging purpose.
So here you can dump the logs from the system, and this log will be used by the developers using ADB
to see what's happening with the system UI.
So, for example, if they find something wrong with the navigation bar on the status bar and if they
want to find out what exactly happening to the system, then they could dump these log within ADB and
then they could get.
So this is basically to assist the debugging.
And then we have our own boot completed this iconic callback, and this is basically to handle that
even when the board is complete.
So any subclass which extends the system UI has to take care of these methods.
So let's have a look at some of the pluses which it stands.
System UI, entrepreneurship def.
Find.
Extends.
System, right?
You.
Well, here you go.
We can see all these all these classes here, like the volume UI, green declarations, render services,
system actions, window magnification.
All these are actually part of the system UI in the Toast UI and the Notification Channel our UI.
So there are a lot of the classes which actually extends the system UI.
Let's open up a volume UI and see how it is implemented.
So it's extending system UI.
It has already done the start method, which is an abstract method.
And here it has defined the logic for that and on on configuration change, it has implemented these
particular loads and also for dumping the law as written this court.
So maybe we can have a quick look at some other clauses, so let's open up most UI.
That should be a simple one.
So in the start method.
It has defined this logic here the functions to hand a shortlist and hide those two things.
It doesn't need to react to any system state it has not implemented other methods.
OK.
Let's take party, right?
So the body may extensive stimuli, it also implements command guilt.
OK, so let's see, the stock method is defined here.
And on configuration change is defined here.
And then it has some other custom logic to find the battery level and all those other stuff which is
required to implement why it's great and should also have a method similarities.
So it is also printing all this out to the output so that the developers can ensure all the system UI
components share some similar behavior, and due to that reason, we have an abstract class old system
UI and this is some UI is extended by most of the system UI components.